<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John Hatcliff&#39;s Homepage</title>
    <link>https://hatcliff.santoslab.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on John Hatcliff&#39;s Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://hatcliff.santoslab.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://hatcliff.santoslab.org/bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hatcliff.santoslab.org/bio/</guid>
      <description>John Hatcliff &amp;ndash; Bio Sketch Bio Sketch - To be Completed</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://hatcliff.santoslab.org/funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hatcliff.santoslab.org/funding/</guid>
      <description>Recent Funding MAILLE: Microkernal Application Information fLow with Logic-based Enforcement
John Hatcliff (K-State PI) with Robby (co-PI); and Todd Carpenter (Lead PI) at Adventium Labs.
U.S. Air Force Research Laboratory (AFRL) Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Phase II. Project total: $749,957 (K-State&amp;rsquo;s portion: $347,000). Duration: May 2021 - April 2023.
SIRFUR: Software Implementation from Rigorous Formal Usable Requirements
John Hatcliff (K-State PI), with Robby (co-PI); and Todd Carpenter (Lead PI) at Adventium Labs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://hatcliff.santoslab.org/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hatcliff.santoslab.org/overview/</guid>
      <description>Overview I&amp;rsquo;m a University Distinguished Professor and Lucas-Rathbone Professor of Engineering (brief bio sketch,full CV) in the Computer Science Department at Kansas State University, and (along with Professor Robby) I lead the laboratory for Specification, Analysis, and Transformation of Software (SAnToS). SAnToS aims to develop and mature technologies and tools for effective construction of high-confidence software systems.
SAnToS Laboratory emphasizes a research methodology in which research advances are achieved by building robust tools that can be applied to and evaluated against real systems in the context of realistic development practices, and then using insights gained in these evaluations to guide future research directions and priorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://hatcliff.santoslab.org/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hatcliff.santoslab.org/papers/</guid>
      <description>Recent Papers Jason Belt, John Hatcliff, Robby, John Shackleton, Jim Carciofini, Todd Carpenter, Eric Mercer, Isaac Amundson, Junaid Babar, Darren Cofer, David Hardin, Karl Hoech, Konrad Slind, Ihor Kuz, Kent Mcleod. &amp;ldquo;Model-Driven Development for the seL4 Microkernel Using the HAMR Framework&amp;rdquo;. Journal of Systems Architecture 134 (102789), January 2023.
John Hatcliff, Jerome Hugues, Danielle Stewart, and Lutz Wrage. &amp;ldquo;Formalization of the AADL Run-Time Services&amp;rdquo;. 11th International Symposium On Leveraging Applications of Formal Methods, Verification and Validation” (ISoLA 2022) LNCS 13702.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://hatcliff.santoslab.org/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hatcliff.santoslab.org/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Current HAMR - lead architect of HAMR (High-Assurance Modeling and Rapid engineering) - a model-driven development framework for high-assurance systems. HAMR is being used in several of US Department of Defense research projects (AFRL, US Army, DARPA). See one of my overview talks on HAMR
Slang and Logika - I support my colleague Professor Robby, in the use and application of Slang (a high-assurance of Scala) and Logika (a highly automated and user-friendly code contract verification tool for Slang).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://hatcliff.santoslab.org/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hatcliff.santoslab.org/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Teaching CIS 301: Logical Foundations of Programming
This course teaches the basic elements found in a formal logic including syntax for claims and rules for making deductions, as well as on how to judge if the rules are suitable in the sense that they only lead to claims that match the reality of the domain that are being reasoned. The focus will be on formal logics for reasoning about program behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
